*   
        
        Donate Now
        
        Where Most Needed
        
        Where Most Needed - 012000

        * * * *

DONATE

* * Donate Now
        
        Where Most Needed
        
        Where Most Needed - 012000

* * * * *
        
    * * * *

Privacy Policy

At The Samaritans Purse—Canada (“SPC”), we are committed to maintaining the accuracy, confidentiality and security of your personal information. This Privacy Policy describes the personal information that we collect from or about you through this website and how we use, and to whom we disclose that information.

SPC has adopted a series of Privacy Policies in order to address the specific privacy concerns of certain groupings of individuals. This Privacy Policy applies to how we collect, use and disclose the personal information of those individuals who visit this website. We have developed our External Privacy Policy with respect to our guests, customers, suppliers and other parties with whom we interact. Our External Privacy Policy is available from our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)).

If you are unsure of which Privacy Policy applies to you, please contact our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)) for more information.

**Privacy Policy Effective for Canada**  
It is SPC’s policy to comply with the applicable privacy legislation within each jurisdiction in which we operate. Sometimes the privacy legislation and/or an individual’s right to privacy are different from one jurisdiction to another. This Privacy Policy covers only those activities that are subject to the provisions of Canada’s federal and provincial privacy laws, as applicable.

This Privacy Policy has a limited scope and application. Consequently, the rights and obligations contained in this Privacy Policy may not be available to all individuals or in all jurisdictions.

**What is Personal Information?**  
For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, personal information is any information about an identifiable individual, other than an individual’s business contact information when collected, used or disclosed for the purposes of enabling the individual to be contacted in relation to their business responsibilities.

**What Personal Information Do We Collect?  
**We collect information from you in the following ways:

* Our use of cookies (please see our section below title How we use Cookies);
* When you make a donation to us (which may be financial or non-financial/in-kind), or respond to our mailings and appeals;
* When you request information or materials from our organization;
* When you contact us in relation to volunteering or fundraising on our behalf;
* When you apply for a job with us, become an employee, or provide consultancy services directly to us; or
* When you contact us with inquiries or other correspondence (including via social media) or become involved with us in another way.

If you interact with us in one of the ways listed above, we may collect and process personal information about you such as:

* Your name, address, email address, telephone number, your age;
* Information you enter onto our website or other hard copy forms at an event;
* Records of your correspondence with us, if you have contacted us;
* Details of your visit to our website, including your IP address, general location;
* Financial information such as your bank or credit card details;
* Whether you have a relationship to another supporter (e.g. husband/wife)

We do not collect “sensitive personal data” about you, such as religious beliefs, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health, unless there is a legitimate reason to do so. If we need to collect this type of data, we will obtain your consent or draw this specifically to your attention so you understand what information is needed and why we need it.

There are times we receive information about you from other sources. Your information may be given to us by third parties, such as online tracking technologies. Collecting information in this manner allows us to collect statistics about our websites’ usage and effectiveness and to personalize your experience while you are on our third-party websites (please see titled “How we use cookies” section).

These third parties are subject to their own policies on data protection and privacy. It is a good idea to check their privacy policy when you provide your information to them to fully understand how they will process your data and may share it with others.

**How Do We Use Cookies?  
**Like most websites, we use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website places on the hard drive of your computer when you visit the website. Cookies do not harm your computer. Cookies may involve the transmission of information from us to you and from you directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its privacy policy. We may use cookies to bring together information we collect about you. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you may not have access to many features that make your guest experience more engaging and some of our services may not function properly.

We use the following types of cookies and online tracking technologies:

* A persistent cookie allows us to provide you with a smoother browsing experience while you navigate our websites. Persistent cookies also help our websites remember your information and settings whenever you visit them. These cookies remain on your hard drive until you manually erase them or they expire.
* A session cookie is temporary, only used during a single session on this website, and is automatically deleted at the end of your visit. We may use session cookies (a) to customize your visit to this website and your membership experience, (b) to deliver content consistent with your stated interests and the manner in which you browse and/or use this website, and (c) for other purposes to make your visit more convenient
* Web Beacons, Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of websites and emails. Web beacons may involve the transmission of information directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its privacy policy. We may use web beacons to bring together information we collect about you

If you click on a hyperlink from our website to any third party websites (e.g. if you “share” content from our website with friends or colleagues on social media), you may be sent cookies from these third party websites. They will do so pursuant to their own policies on privacy and cookies. It is a good idea to check their privacy policies to fully understand their use of cookies.

By using our website, you consent to our use of cookies, which are updated from time to time. The cookies will be stored on your device (unless rejected or disabled by your browser).

Internet Browsers normally accept cookies by default. However, it is possible to set an internet browser to reject cookies. If you do not accept our use of cookies as set out in this policy, please set your internet browser to reject cookies. This may impair your ability to use our website so that some features may not work.

We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer for purposes that are unrelated to the service being offered through your interaction with this website.

We may update our use of cookies from time to time so please check this policy regularly.

**What about Online Advertising?  
**We promote and encourage support of our ministry activities by purchasing advertising space on third-party websites via companies such as Google, Bing, and Facebook.

When you visit one of our websites, we or a third party may place one or more types of cookies on your computer in order to recognize your computer. Because we advertise about our ministry activities on third-party websites, we are able to compile anonymous information over time about the types of pages, content, and ads you or others who use your computer visited or viewed. This anonymous information is used for many purposes. For example, it helps us try to ensure that you do not see the same advertisements repeatedly. We also use this anonymous information to help select and display targeted advertisements on third-party websites that encourage support of our ministry activities.

Third-party companies also may collect anonymous information about your activity on our websites and applications and on third-party web sites and applications using online tracking technologies like cookies, web beacons, pixels or other storage technologies. Tracking data collected by these third-party companies is used to decide which advertisements you see on third-party websites and applications, but does not identify you personally.

You may choose not to receive targeted advertisements from many ad networks, data exchanges, marketing analytics and other service providers by visiting the following links:

* Google: See [Device Settings](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/1660762#mob), [Marketing Platform opt-out page](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en#display_optout).
* Bing: See the [Microsoft Online Advertising Privacy Statement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-US/privacystatement)

Other Advertisers (such as Facebook):  you can opt out of advertisers [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance opt out page](https://youradchoices.ca/en/tools).

**What about Links to other Websites?  
**Our website may contain links to other websites that may be subject to less stringent privacy standards. We cannot assume any responsibility for the privacy practices, policies or actions of the third parties that operate these websites. SPC is not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information. You should review the privacy policies of these websites before providing them with personal information.

To allow you to interact with third-party websites on which you may have accounts (such as social media websites) or join communities on such websites, we may provide links or embed third-party applications that allow you to login, post content, or join communities from our website.

**Why Do We Collect, Use, and Disclose Personal Information?  
**The personal information collected through our website is used and disclosed for our ministry and business purposes. For example, we may collect, use and disclose your personal information to:

1. Establish, maintain and manage relationships so that we may provide you with updates about our programs and projects (i.e. monthly newsletters, special mailings, and email etc.) or receive from us the products and services that you have requested;
2. Encourage you spiritually;
3. Provide you the opportunity to support our work through prayer, donations and personal participation in ministry work;
4. Allow us to review the products and services provided so that we may work to improve them;
5. For our own administrative purposes and to keep a record of your relationship with us.
6. To provide essential event information where you have signed up to attend.
7. Be able to comply with your requests (for example, your communication preferences);
8. To ensure the content from our website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your compute/mobile device.
9. Protect us against error, fraud, theft and damage to our property; and
10. Enable us to comply with applicable law or regulatory process (for example, we may collect personal information to satisfy the obligations imposed on us by our various regulators).

We may also collect, use and disclose your personal information for any other reasonable purpose to which you consent.

Your personal information may be shared with our employees, contractors, consultants, affiliates, ministry partners and other parties who require such information to assist us with: (i) establishing, maintaining and managing our relationship with you; and (ii) providing the products and services you request.

Moreover, your personal information may be disclosed to third parties outside of Canada. For example, Samaritan’s Purse, a non-profit corporation based in the United States, may provide certain information technology, data processing services, and consulting services to us from time to time. As a result, your personal information may be collected, used, processed, stored or disclosed in the United States.

When leaving our website or upon the collection of data for shared programs and services we will inform you and request your consent prior to directing you to their website or submitting your information to such third parties. In these circumstances the information you submit or we deliver on your behalf will be handled and stored subject to the privacy policies of the third party.

Please note that we may collect, use or disclose your personal information without your knowledge or consent where we are permitted or required by applicable law or regulatory requirements to do so.

**Your Consent is Important to Us  
**By using our website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as explained in this Privacy Policy.

You may change or withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice, by contacting our Privacy Manager using the contact information set out below. All communications with respect to such withdrawal or variation of consent should be in writing and addressed to our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)).

Please note that in some circumstances, withdrawing or changing your consent to certain uses of your personal information may affect: (i) our ability to provide you with the products or services you request; and (ii) your ability to access to this website.

When you request to withdraw your consent we will keep some basic information in order to avoid sending you unwanted communications in the future. If we do not retain this information, then this could result in us contacting you again as we would no longer have a record of your request not to be contacted.

**How is Your Personal Information Protected?  
**SPC endeavors to maintain physical, technical and procedural safeguards that are appropriate to the sensitivity of the personal information in question. These safeguards are designed to prevent your personal information from loss and unauthorized access, copying, use, modification or disclosure.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while this website strives to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once this website receives your transmission, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems.

The security of your personal information is important to us, please advise our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)) immediately of any incident involving the loss of or unauthorized access to or disclosure of personal information that is in our custody or control.

**Where we store your information  
**The information we collect from you is stored in Canada. When we need to transfer your data to a destination outside of Canada, information will be handled and stored subject to the privacy policies of the third party.

**Updating Your Personal Information  
**It is important that the information contained in our records is both accurate and current. If your personal information happens to change during the course of our relationship, please keep us informed of such changes.

In some circumstances, we may not agree with your request to change your personal information and will instead append an alternative text to the record in question.

**Access to Your Personal Information  
**You can ask to see your personal information. If you want to review, verify or correct your personal information, please contact our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)). Please note that any such communication must be in writing.

When requesting access to your personal information, please note that we may request specific information from you to enable us to confirm your identity and right to access, as well as to search for and provide you with the personal information that we hold about you. We may charge you a fee to access your personal information; subject to regulatory rules in your jurisdiction, however, we will advise you of any fee in advance. If you require assistance in preparing your request, please contact our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)).

Your right to access the personal information that we hold about you is not absolute. There are instances where applicable law or regulatory requirements allow or require us to refuse to provide some or all of the personal information that we hold about you. In addition, the personal information may have been destroyed, erased or made anonymous in accordance with our record retention obligations and practices. In the event that we cannot provide you with access to your personal information, we will endeavor to inform you of the reasons why, subject to any legal or regulatory restrictions.

**Inquiries or Concerns?**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or concerns about how we manage your personal information, please contact our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)) by telephone, in writing or by e-mail. We will endeavor to answer your questions and advise you of any steps taken to address the issues raised by you. If you are dissatisfied with our response, you may be entitled to make a written submission to the Privacy Commissioner in your jurisdiction.

**Privacy Manager**  
We have appointed a Privacy Manager to oversee compliance with this Privacy Policy. The contact information for our Privacy Manager is as follows:

Privacy Manager  
The Samaritan’s Purse Canada  
20 Hopewell Way NE  
Calgary, AB T3J 5H5  
Fax: (403) 250-6567  
E-mail: [\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Revisions to this Privacy Policy  
**SPC from time to time, may make changes to this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in its legal or regulatory obligations or in the manner in which we deal with your personal information. We will post any revised version of this Privacy Policy on our website and we encourage you to refer back to it on a regular basis. This Privacy Policy was last updated on August 30, 2019.

**Interpretation of this Privacy Policy  
**Any interpretation associated with this Privacy Policy will be made by our Privacy Manager ([\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)). This Privacy Policy includes examples but is not intended to be restricted in its application to such examples; therefore where the word “including” is used, it shall mean “including without limitation”.

This Privacy Policy does not create or confer upon any individual any rights, or impose upon SPC any rights or obligations outside of, or in addition to, any rights or obligations imposed by Canada’s federal and provincial privacy laws, as applicable. Should there be, in a specific case, any inconsistency between this Privacy Policy and Canada’s federal and provincial privacy laws, as applicable, this Privacy Policy shall be interpreted, in respect of that case, to give effect to, and comply with, such privacy laws.

[](javascript:void((function(){var%20e=document.createElement('script');e.setAttribute('type','text/javascript');e.setAttribute('charset','UTF-8');e.setAttribute('src','https://assets.pinterest.com/js/pinmarklet.js?r='+Math.random()*99999999);document.body.appendChild(e)})());)

[\[email protected\]](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Who We Are

After sharing the story of the Good Samaritan, Jesus said “Go and do likewise.” That is the mission of Samaritan's Purse—to follow the example of Christ by helping those in need and proclaiming the hope of the Gospel.

Top Stories

[Samaritan’s Purse Responding after Alberta Tornado Damages Several Homes](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/article/samaritans-purse-responding-after-alberta-tornado-damages-several-homes/)

[Finding Precious Heirloom Gives Joy to Nova Scotia Wildfire Survivor](https://www.samaritanspurse.ca/article/finding-precious-heirloom-gives-joy-to-nova-scotia-wildfire-victim/)

STAY IN THE KNOW
----------------

Join our email subscriber list and get exclusive updates about how God is working through Samaritan’s Purse, thanks to supporters like you.

Be the first to read and see our stories from the field. Lives are being changed every day! Learn how you can pray and contribute to what we’re doing. Hear about volunteer opportunities, mission trips and other ways you can get involved. Sign up here:

Don't worry, we hate spam as much as you do. We will never sell or share your email address.

© Copyright 2024 Samaritan's Purse Canada. All rights reserved.  
  
Samaritan's Purse Canada  
20 Hopewell Way NE  
Calgary, Alberta, T3J 5H5  

Canada Revenue Agency registration #: BN 11913 8527 RR0001

### STAY IN THE KNOW!

Join our email subscriber list and get exclusive updates about how God is working through Samaritan’s Purse, thanks to supporters like you.

Be the first to read and see our stories from the field. Lives are being changed every day! Learn how you can pray and contribute to what we’re doing. Hear about volunteer opportunities, mission trips and other ways you can get involved. Sign up here:

Don't worry, we hate spam as much as you do. We will never sell or share your email address.

STAY IN THE KNOW!
-----------------

Join our email subscriber list and get exclusive updates about how God is working through Samaritan’s Purse, thanks to supporters like you.

Be the first to read and see our stories from the field. Lives are being changed every day! Learn how you can pray and contribute to what we’re doing. Hear about volunteer opportunities, mission trips and other ways you can get involved. Sign up here:

Don’t worry, we hate spam as much as you do. We will never sell or share your email address.
